Guide to the Richard L. Schlegel papers, 1960-1980
Schlegel, Richard L. papers, 1960-1980
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Richard L. Schlegel papers, [ca. 1960-1980]
7306
Richard LaMar Schlegel
11.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, clippings, drafts of articles, legal briefs, business papers and records, subject files, photographs, film.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Legal files pertaining to SCHLEGEL VS U.S., 1961-1969; files relating to PACE! A DIGEST OF SEX AND HUMOR, 1970; subject files on sexual topics in general and homosexual topics in particular; and erotic photographs and other materials.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Gay activist and editor and publisher of gay magazines. Born in Berrysburg, Pennsylvania, February 11, 1927 and died February 25, 2006.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Legal files, 1961-1969, pertaining to Schlegel vs U.S., a court case relating to Schlegel dismissal from U.S. Army employment and 1970 files relating to Pace! A Digest of Sex and Humor, for which Schlegel served as editor and co-publisher, including letters to the editor, business correspondence, and materials concerning the finances and advertising. Also, correspondence, erotic photographs and writing, and information on models collected for possible publication, some of which (when noted) came from John W. Emmerson (born April 23,1920, died April 18,1986) from Battle Creek, Michigan. Also clippings, a subject file, magazines, and books on sexual topics in general and homosexual topics in particular.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schlegel, Richard L.; United States.--Armed Forces--Gays.
Subjects:
Homosexuality.; Gay men.; Sex (Psychology).; Homosexuality--Law and legislation.; Gays--Employment.; Homosexuality and literature.; Sex oriented businesses.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 9-10: restricted until 2035. Box 11: restricted until 2030. Boxes 9-10: materials in these boxes may not be reproduced or put online.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence and Personal Files
Box 1, folders 1-14; Box 6, folders 1-52; Box 7, folders 1-24; Box 8, folders 14-15, 22-25
Series II. Legal files
Box 2, folders 1-60; Box 3; Box 7, folder 33; Box 8, folders 16-18
Series III. Subject files
Box 3, folders 1-40; Box 4, folders 1-40; Box 7, folders 25-35; Box 8, folders 1-13, 19-21, 26-34; Box 12, folders 1-2, 4; Box 14
Series IV. Pace! files
Box 4, folders 41-52; Box 5, folders 1-24; Box 12, folders 3, 15-18
Series V. Erotica
Box 9, folders 1-45; Box 10, folders 1-69; Box 11, folders 1-40; Box 12, folders 5-14, 19-33; Box 13
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence and Personal Files
  - Richard L. Schlegel Correspondence, 1960-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - Richard L. Schlegel Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with John Emmerson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with De Wayne Bethany, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with District 11 Court Clerk, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Ted Ellsworth, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Mrs. E. L. Emmerson, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Win Fullford, 1955-1975 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Buel Godwin, 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Terry, ca.1940-1950 (Box 6, Folder 22-24)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Henry Peter Kulish, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Geo Lang, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Chas Montague, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Tom Myrick, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Ted Patterson, 1952-1958, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Leslie "Les" Smith, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Richard Sommer, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Veterans Administration Hospital, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Edward "Eddie" Walsh, 1947-1958 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Vincent Welty, 1949-1959 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Harold Wright, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Tom (?), 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Lewis and Cindy Carroll, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - John Emmerson Correspondence with Jane Seamans, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous John Emmerson Correspondence, ca.1940-1980 (Box 6, Folder 37-40)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, 1940s (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous Richard Schlegel Correspondence, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - News and Media Clippings (Box 6, Folder 48-52)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Daniel Maheval, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence between Kenneth Doolin and Bobby Kent, sent to Schlegel, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tape from Kenneth Doolin to Richard Schlegel, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Kenneth Doolin, 1987-1988, 1994-5 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Marc Stein, 1993-1995, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Nancy Cook, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with James McCoid, 1962, 1969, 1983, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Chet Leach, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Margaret Schlegel Correspondence, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Sen. Edward Helfrick, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Walt Burgess, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Don McLeod, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Vincent Welty, 1961, 1963-1965, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Franklin Kameny, 1988, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Homer Hathaway, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Allen E. Kline, 1949-1950, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with L. Roy Fisher, 1946, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Dr. Hudson, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Schlegel Correspondence with Robert Keller, 1949-1963 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Schlegel Contact Book, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Series II. Legal files
  - Schlegel vs. United States. Ct. Cl. 369-63, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Schlegel vs. United States. Ct. Cl. 369-63, Additional Legal Documents, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2-15)
  - Schlegel vs. United States. Ct. Cl. 369-63, Appeal, Legal Memoranda, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Handwritten notes by Schlegel re: Court Case, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts and Typescripts re: Legal Questions and Homosexuality, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Background Material, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Franklin E. Kameny - Campaign Materials, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Boutilier Decision, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Scott Decision, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Prior Conduct, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Police Power, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Special Competence, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Silence Not Presuming Guilt, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Precedents, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Confrontation and Cross Examination, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Coerced Confessions, 1961-68 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Void for Vagueness Fair Warning, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Regulations, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
  - Regulatory, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Rules of the Court, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Case Research, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lt. Colonel Perry, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Colonel Sams, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Discovery, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Extra Copies - Court of Claims Materials, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39-41)
  - Inconsistent Official Positions, 1961-62 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Offer of Proof - Sams, Perry, Mays, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Department of Defense Project, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
  - Schlegel, Richard L., 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
  - Miscellaneous Background Material re: Schlegel vs. United States, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 48-60)
  - Several Briefs, Findings, and Other Printed Documents Pertaining to Law (Box 3)
  - Schlegel Research and Correspondence into Government Professional Dismissal, 1959-1993 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Statements about Dismissal from Riddles, Jordan and Deller, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Lupold Court Case with Schlegel Testimony, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Materials Pertaining to Case Pennsylvania v. Norman Gundrum, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Series III. Subject files
  - "Code of Behavior for Military Personnel," by Richard L. Schlegel, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speech Delivered to Mattachine Society Convention, San Francisco by Richard L. Schlegel. Reprinted in Mattachine Review that year., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "A Heterosexual Viewpoint," by Peter Genung, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - East Coast Homophile Organizations: "How to Handle a Federal Interrogation", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Second Draft of Suggested Cover Letter to Organizations Invited to Edit and Endorse the Petition, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Society for Individual Rights (SIR!), with "Vector," vol. 1, no. 2, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mattachine Society of New York; "New York Mattachine Society Newsletters", 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mattachine Society of Washington, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Daughters of Bilitis convention program, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Homosexuality and the Law," issues by the Homosexual Law Reform Society, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Man and Society," published by The Albany Trust, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - One, Incorporated, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Janus Society of America, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
  - Mattachine Society of San Francisco, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - East Coast Homophile Organizations (ECHO); "Eastern Mattachine Magazine", 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Computer Project: SIECUS (Sex Information and Education Council of the United States), "Sexology" article, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18-22)
  - Gay Moments in Advertising, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Capitol Q", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Personal Publications and Organization Liaison, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Stag Line Zodiac Calendar 1966, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Sex Education, 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 27-29)
  - Thane Project, including "Tangents" and "The Prosperos Newsletter", 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Conjugal Visitation and Sex in Prison, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Sexual Humor, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 32-35)
  - Sex in Advertising, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36-39)
  - Personal Reading, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Library; including booklists and book advertising, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Clippings, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Research Through a Glass, Darkly," by Fritz a. Fluckinger; "New York Mattachine Newsletter," and Clippings, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, publications, drafts, lists, newlsetters, and other printed material pertaining to sexuality and homosexuality, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 8-22)
  - Homosexuality and lesbianism, including drafts of articles, drafts of Schlegel correspondence ad miscellaneous printed material, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Clippings, publications, drafts, lists, newsletters, and other printed material pertaining to sexuality, lesbianism and homosexuality, including Mattachine bulletins, the National League for Social Understanding, and other miscellaneous irregular publications. Also, letters from Schlegel from the American Academy for International Morality, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 25-40)
  - [untitled book of musings] by Romayne, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Susquehanna Lambda Newsletters, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Susquehanna Lambda Support Group Materials, ca. 1990 (Box 7, Folder 27-28)
  - Schlegel Education Materials, esp. Post-Secondary (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Schlegel Thesis Materials (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
  - Draft of "A Brief History of Gay" by Don McLeod (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Military Materials, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
  - Employment - Applications, 1950-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Employment - Orientation and Training, 1951-1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Employment - Notes and Clippings, 1950-1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Employment - Literature, 1950-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Employment - Resumes, 1950-1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Employment - Correspondence, 1950-1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Schlegel - Financial Materials, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Frank Kameny Materials, 1981-1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Academy for International Morality Materials, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sophisticated Fashion Inc., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Tahiti U-Drive Inc., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Schlegel-Deibler Memorial Endowment, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sesquehanna Kontact Magazines and correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - A Brief History of Gay materials, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Richard Schlegel and Friends, Family pictures, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - M.A. Dissertation: "Radio Station WTOP Management in the Public Interest," by Richard Schlegel, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "The Air Coordinating Committee: An Illustration of Successful Interdepartmental Cooperation," by Richard Schlegel, Civil Aeronautics Administration, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Articles relating to homosexuality, mental illness, censorship, etc., 1950-1960s (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Photos, including military photos, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Business closings and sales flyers, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Marsden Photo to Schlegel, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - East Coast Homophile Organization Conference Pamphlets, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - "Beginners Guide to Cruising", "Drawing the Nude", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Homosexual Organizations and Rights Materials, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Gay International, Tricks of the Trade, Gay Male Swinger, ca. 1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Friend-to-Friend Club, Mattachine Review, Like Young, Drum, The Ladder, etc., ca. 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hypnosis Diary, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Schlegel Boxes of Personal Film Rolls (with Photo Keys), n.d. (Box 14)
  - "Vince on TV News" Recording Reel, n.d. (Box 14)
  - "DN - Roger Bob Marsels" Recording Reel, n.d. (Box 14)
  - "Very DN - Jeff gets B. 3 3/4 good. Save" Recording Reel, July 1979 (Box 14)
  - Emmerson - "Tom Detroit" Movie Film, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Emmerson - "Bobby V.G." Movie Film, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Emmerson - "Me - Army and New York" Movie Film, 1960 (Box 14)
  - "Physique Film" Movie Film, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Emmerson - Movie Film (untitled), n.d. (Box 14)
- Series IV. Pace! files
  - Pace! Magazine prospectus, stockholding papers, and correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Pace! Magazine business correspondence, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Pace! Magazine letters to the editor, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Pace! Magazine material pertaining to advertising, submissions, articles, and business, c. 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 44-52)
  - Pace! Magazine business and advertising correspondence, including story and cartoon submissions, and letters to Drum Magazine, c. 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1-24)
  - Pace! Magazine copies, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Pace and Swinger Ads, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Pace and Swinger Ad - Dial a Model, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Pace Magazine Photos, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Pace Magazine Layout with Photographs, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Series V. Erotica
  - Anthropometric Measures and Physical Features materials, ca. 1948 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Emmerson - Physical Features records, ca. 1950 (Box 12, Folder 6-9)
  - News Clippings and Notes Relating to Models, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Emmerson - Personal Data and Notes on Models, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 36-43)
  - Personal Data and News Clippings, 1960-1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Personal Data - Florida Pictures, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Personal Data Records, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - John Emmerson - Battle Creek, MI - Categorized Personal Data and Photos, by Number, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 5-47)
  - John Emmerson - Battle Creek, MI - Miscellaneous Categorized Personal Data and Photos, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - John Emmerson - Battle Creek, MI - Anthropometric Figures and Name Lists, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Various Consent Forms, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Envelopes of Model Pubic Hair (scans of the envelopes only), 1959, 1960, 1961, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - John Emmerson pictures, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Photo Negatives, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Portrait Photos, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Erotica Photos, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4-31)
  - Other Erotica Photos, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Erotica Photos, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Erotica Negatives, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Erotica Photos, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Erotica Photos, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1-12)
  - Emmerson Erotica Photos, 1968, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 22-40)
  - Schlegel Photo Slides for Pace, Swinger, Drum, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10-13)
  - Schlegel Large Photo Slides, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Emmerson Erotica Photos, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 50-69)
  - Emmerson Erotica Photos, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 19-33)
  - Erotic Literature, by Walt Burgess, sent to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Robbie's Fun," Erotic Story by W. Esbee, Submitted by Walt Burgess, sent to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Brothers Three," Erotic Story by W. Esbee, Submitted by Walt Burgess, sent to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - "Another Kind of Love Story," written by W. Essbee, submitted by Walt Burgess to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "Helping the Judge," written by W. Esbee (Walt Burgess), to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "You Never Can Tell," written by W. Esbee (Walt Burgess), to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Some Cops Do," written by W. Esbee (Walt Burgess), to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "Hitchhikers' Delights," written by W. Esbee (Walt Burgess), to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Fortunate Accident," written by W. Esbee (Walt Burgess), to Schlegel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Erotica Photograph Scrapbooks - John Emmerson, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Personal Data on Models - John Emmerson, n.d. (Box 13)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Cataloged in Human Sexuality Collection except items marked with an asterisk.
A Brief History of GAY: Canada's First Gay Tabloid by Donald McLeod
Day Is Ending: A Doctor's Love Shattered by Alzheimer's Disease, signed by author Walt Meyer*
Going for the Green: Selling in the 21st Century, signed by author Walt Meyer*
Trailblazing: America's First Openly Gay High School Coach, signed by author Eric Anderson